MOMOH ABDUL JABBAR

Full stack Developer

- momohabduljabbar@gmail.com
- +2347066986305
- Suncity estate, Abuja, Nigeria.
- **1** 01/02/1995
- Nigerian
- in https://www.linkedin.com/in/momoh-abdul-jabbar-183260161
- https://medium.com/@momohabduljabbar
- Male
- ▼ VINTAGE JAB#4494
- github.com/jabbarlee
- https://stackoverflow.com/users/19784453/jabbarlee?tab=profile
- https://jabbar-portfolio.netlify.app

Profile

I am Momoh Abdul Jabbar, also known as a coding machine because I code for a duration of about eleven hours daily. I am a full stack developer, digital marketer and a web 3 enthusiast. I will use my qualities and skills to promote any organization or body as well as contribute tremendously to the strategic growth and development of the establishment where the set aims and objectives would be exceeded by my expertise and willingness to learn and improve. Here is my Portfolio website https://jabbar-portfolio.netlify.app 🗅

Professional Experience

02/2022 – 02/2023

Remote

FRONTEND DEVELOPER, woof Solana

- Worked on the company's web features.
- Tested and refined software with the team leads prior to rollout.
- Collaborated with frontend engineers and UI/UX designers to create easily accessible web experiences
- Got exposed to web 3 development

01/2019 – 10/2021 ABUJA, NIGERIA

FULL STACK DEVELOPER/SOCIAL MEDIA MARKETER THRIVE DIGITAL

 worked together with the team to build the frontend and the backend of company website using tools like react.js, nextjs, and we used sanity content management system for the backend .we used Graphql as the query language.



• i was also in charge of the Content marketing, using mobile phones or small gadgets to grow business, Strategy and planning and the Email marketing of the entire company

04/2018 – 12/2018 remote

FULL STACK DEVELOPER FREELANCER, Self Employed

- Delivered professional websites using HTML5, CSS3 (+ SCSS, BEM),
 JavaScript and React best practices.
- Improved website performance by compressing, caching and lazy loading images and components
- Included SEO, responsive, multi-platform and hosting support, enabling their website to be used by any

browser or device in the world

01/2018 – 04/2018 Abuja, Nigeria

FRONT END DEVELOPER/SOCIAL MEDIA INFLUENCER FMG WEALTH

COMPANY, Francis Okumagba

- I was incharge of all social media handles of the company
- i worked as a content marketing expert
- enhanced the company through search engine optimisation
- i was the digital marketing manager of FMG.
- Development great web solution through collaborations with my fellow developers using react and most in demand skills.

2017

MINNA, NIGER STATE, NIGERIA

WEB MAINTAINER /I.T SPECIALIST, MINISTRY OF WOMEN'S AFFAIRS MINNA

NIGER STATE, Mr Sulieman

- In charge of documenting issues relating to women in Niger state, e.g illnesses like breast cancer.
- Computer software installations
- Computer maintenance.
- website maintainance

2016

AUCHI, EDO, NIGERIA

MANAGEMENT AND INFORMATION SYSTEM UNIT(MIS), Mr kester O Omoregie

I was instructed to keep track of the following

- Record keeping and management of school MIS records
- Examining data processing /Analysis.

2016

Abuja, Nigeria

INDUSTRIAL TRAINING AT THE CENTRAL BANK OF NIGERIA (CBN),

Mr kazeem, Mr chima.

My time in the central bank of Nigeria Was Amazing i was In charge of

- hardware maintenance including printers, monitors etc.
- Software installations
 I was part of the I.T personnels who installed new software on the computers for both new and active members on each departments in the central bank of Nigeria.
- Network administrator
 I was in charge of installing, configuring, mai and optimization of networks and communication links.

Projects

2023

01/2023 **MEDIUM CLONE WEBSITE,** Medium app building challenge ♂

Medium is a platform i love alot. This app was built using firebase ,tailwind css, html. it supports user authentication and an identical user interface as the origin medium app.

I came about builing this web app as a challenge from a friend who said i can never build a web app which looks like medium app visually

JABBAR'S BLOG, favourite blog for everything information □

I had a lot of fun time creating my personal Blog. i am a someone who does not like to miss out in some of the most important information around so I thought why not create a blog that others can also benefit from.

This is my official blog, where I share everything about Information, ranging from tech, politics, religion, lifestyle. i created this using nextjs, tailwindcss, sanity and hosted on varcel.

11/2022 PIZZA ORDERING APP ☑

I love pizza's . Who doesn't love pizza? I was learning framer motion and i taught to myself why not create a pizza related app using the knowledge I have from framer motion and react.js. It was created using html, CSS and framer motion and deployed on netlify.

2022 **SATISFACTION EATERY** ☑

This is my first trial to using Tailwind css. i wanted to build a simple responsive webpage. This page was built with only tailwind css, html and svg images.

Mongo db

Skills

Javascript	React.js
Node.js	Html
Css	React redux
GraphQL	Tailwind css
Next.js	Digital marketing
Discord Defi and nft moderator	Content marketing, search engine optimisation,
TypeScript	email marketing, social media marketing.
Sanity	framer-motion
Firebase	Api's

Certificates

- Google digital skills for Africa ☑
- WAEC, West African Examination Council
- World class ict solutions, Web development
- The IC3 certification Digital Literacy certification
- NABTED Nation Business and Technical Examination Board
- World class ict solutions, oracle database management

Languages

English language

I speak good English that in turn help me in facilitating good intelligent conversations.

Interests

Coding, reading, body building, watching movies, video games, problem solving.

References

MR Kester O. Omoregie, *Head of Department computer science, school of I. C. T*, Auchi polytechnic 08034305705, 07030989568

Mrs.Evenlyn Oduntan, *Director*, *M. I. S unit.*, Auchi polytechnic 07031194549,07084792291

Dr Opeyemi Adeyemo, *Lecturer, Department of computer science*, Afe Babalola University 08121592400

Education

1999 – 2005 Edo state, Nigeria	First school leaving certificate, Auchi polytechnic Primary school.
2007 – 2012 Edo state, Nigeria	West African senior school Certificate. Six credits., Auchi Polytechnic Secondary school
2013 – 2016 Ekiti State, Nigeria	B.s.c (Hons) computer science., Afe babalola university
2020 – present Ondo State, Nigeria	Masters Degree (MSC), Adekunle Ajasin University Akungba